Tonight, I want to have a conversation about
أود الحديث هذه الليلة حول
this incredible global issue
هذه القضية العالمية العجيبة
that's at the intersection of land use, food and environment,
التي يتقاطع فيها استخدام الأرض، والغذاء والبيئة،
something we can all relate to,
الشيء الذي نعرفه كلنا،
and what I've been calling the other inconvenient truth.
وما أسميته الحقيقة الأخرى المزعجة.
But first, I want to take you on a little journey.
ولكن في البداية، أود أخذكم في رحلة صغيرة.
Let's first visit our planet, but at night,
دعونا أولا نقوم بزيارة كوكبنا، ولكن ليلا،
and from space.
ومن الفضاء.
This is what our planet looks like from outer space
هذا ما يبدو عليه كوكبنا من الفضاء الخارجي
at nighttime, if you were to take a satellite and travel
ليلا، إن أنتم تجولتم بقمر اصطناعي
around the planet. And the thing you would notice first,
حول الكوكب. فإن أول شيء ستلاحظونه،
of course, is how dominant the human presence
بالطبع، هو هيمنة التواجد البشري
on our planet is.
على كوكبنا.
We see cities, we see oil fields,
سنشاهد المدن، وحقول النفط
you can even make out fishing fleets in the sea,
يمكنكم حتى تمييز أساطيل الصيد في البحر،
that we are dominating much of our planet,
يبدو أننا نسيطر على جزء كبير من كوكبنا،
and mostly through the use of energy
وخاصة من خلال استخدام الطاقة
that we see here at night.
وهو ما نراه هنا في الليل.
But let's go back and drop it a little deeper
ولكن دعونا نعود للوراء ونتعمق قليلا
and look during the daytime.
ونلقي نظرة خلال النهار.
What we see during the day is our landscapes.
ما نشاهده خلال النهار هي المناظر الطبيعية لكوكبنا.
This is part of the Amazon Basin, a place called Rondônia
هذه منطقة من حوض الأمازون وتدعى روندونيا
in the south-center part of the Brazilian Amazon.
بوسط جنوب غابة الأمازون البرازيلية.
If you look really carefully in the upper right-hand corner,
إذا نظرتم بتمعن في الزاوية اليمنى بالأعلى،
you're going to see a thin white line,
فستلحظون خط أبيض رفيع،
which is a road that was built in the 1970s.
هو طريق بني في سنة 1970.
If we come back to the same place in 2001,
وإن عدنا لنفس المكان في 2001.
what we're going to find is that these roads
سنجد أن هذه الطرق
spurt off more roads, and more roads after that,
تؤدي إلى المزيد والمزيد من الطرق بعدها،
at the end of which is a small clearing in the rainforest
في نهايتها بياض صغير بالغابة المطيرة
where there are going to be a few cows.
حيث ستعيش بعض الأبقار.
These cows are used for beef. We're going to eat these cows.
وهذه الأبقار تربى لإنتاج اللحوم. والتي سنستهلكها نحن.
And these cows are eaten basically in South America,
وتستهلك هذه اللحوم أساسا بأمريكا الجنوبية،
in Brazil and Argentina. They're not being shipped up here.
بالبرازيل والأرجنتين. فلا يتم تصديرها إلى هنا.
But this kind of fishbone pattern of deforestation
لكن نمط إزالة الغابات على شكل هيكل سمكة
is something we notice a lot of around the tropics,
هو شيء نلاحظه بكثرة عبر الغابات الاستوائية،
especially in this part of the world.
وخاصة في هذا الجزء من العالم.
If we go a little bit further south in our little tour of the world,
وإن توجهنا أبعد بقليل إلى الجنوب في رحلتنا حول العالم،
we can go to the Bolivian edge of the Amazon,
يمكننا التوجه نحو الحدود البوليفية لغابة الأمازون،
here also in 1975, and if you look really carefully,
هنا أيضا في العام 1975، إن نظرتم بدقة أكبر،
there's a thin white line through that kind of seam,
هناك خط أبيض دقيق يعبر البساط الأخضر،
and there's a lone farmer out there
حي توجد مزرعة وحيدة هناك
in the middle of the primeval jungle.
في وسط الغابة البدائية.
Let's come back again a few years later, here in 2003,
فنعد مجددا إلى السنوات الماضية الأخيرة، وبالضبط 2003،
and we'll see that that landscape actually looks
لنجد أن ذاك المنظر الطبيعي يبدو في الواقع
a lot more like Iowa than it does like a rainforest.
أشبه بكثير لأيوا منه لغابة مطيرة.
In fact, what you're seeing here are soybean fields.
في الحقيقة، ما تشاهدونه هنا هو حقول فول الصويا.
These soybeans are being shipped to Europe and to China
محاصيل فول الصويا هذه تصدر نحو أوروبا والصين
as animal feed, especially after the mad cow disease scare
كعلف للحيوانات، خاصة بعد الذعر الذي سببه مرض جنون البقر
about a decade ago, where we don't want to feed animals
قبل عقد من الزمن، حيث لم نعد نريد إعطاء الحيوانات
animal protein anymore, because that can transmit disease.
بروتين حيواني، لأنه قد ينقل المرض.
Instead, we want to feed them more vegetable proteins.
بل أردنا إعطائهم علف ببروتينات نباتية أكثر.
So soybeans have really exploded,
لذا انتشر فول الصويا بكثرة،
showing how trade and globalization are
مما يبين أن التجارة والعولمة هما
really responsible for the connections to rainforests
المسئولين الحقيقيين عن الروابط بين الغابات المطيرة
and the Amazon -- an incredibly strange
والأمازون -- عالمنا الغريب والمترابط
and interconnected world that we have today.
بشكل لا يصدق اليوم.
Well, again and again, what we find as we look
حسنا، مرة بعد أخرى، ماذا نلاحظ عندما ننظر
around the world in our little tour of the world
للعالم خلال جولتنا الصغيرة،
is that landscape after landscape after landscape
سنرى أن منظرا طبيعيا بعد أخر
have been cleared and altered for growing food
يزال ليعوض بالزراعة الغذائية
and other crops.
والمحاصيل الأخرى.
So one of the questions we've been asking is,
لدى من بين الأسئلة التي طرحناها هي،
how much of the world is used to grow food,
كم هي المساحة المستخدمة بالزراعة الغذائية،
and where is it exactly, and how can we change that
وأين هي بالضبط، وكيف يمكننا تغيير ذلك
into the future, and what does it mean?
في المستقبل، وماذا يعني ذلك؟
Well, our team has been looking at this on a global scale,
لدى درس فريقنا المسألة على نطاق عالمي،
using satellite data and ground-based data kind of to track
مستخدمين بيانات الأقمار الاصطناعية والمراكز الأرضية لتتبع
farming on a global scale.
النشاط الزراعي على نطاق عالمي.
And this is what we found, and it's startling.
وهذا ما وجدناه، وهو مخيف.
This map shows the presence of agriculture
هذه الخريطة تبين انتشار الزراعة
on planet Earth.
على كوكب الأرض.
The green areas are the areas we use to grow crops,
المناطق الخضراء نستخدمها لزراعة المحاصيل،
like wheat or soybeans or corn or rice or whatever.
كالقمح أو فول الصويا أو الذرة أو الأرز وغيرها.
That's 16 million square kilometers' worth of land.
تعادل 16 مليون كلم مربع من الأراضي.
If you put it all together in one place,
إن أنتم وضعتموها جنبا إلى جنب،
it'd be the size of South America.
ستكون بمساحة أمريكا الجنوبية
The second area, in brown, is the world's pastures
المنطقة الثانية، باللون البني، هي المراعي بالعالم
and rangelands, where our animals live.
والمراعي الطبيعية حيث تعيش الحيونات.
That area's about 30 million square kilometers,
تعادل هذه المناطق 30 مليون كلم مربع،
or about an Africa's worth of land,
أو حوالي حجم أفريقيا،
a huge amount of land, and it's the best land, of course,
وبالطبع مساحة هائلة من الأراضي وأجودها،
is what you see. And what's left is, like,
كما تشاهدون. وما تبقى هو
the middle of the Sahara Desert, or Siberia,
وسط الصحراء الكبرى أو سيبيريا،
or the middle of a rain forest.
أو وسط الغابة المطيرة.
We're using a planet's worth of land already.
نحن نستخدم بالفعل ما يعادل كوكبا.
If we look at this carefully, we find it's about 40 percent
إن دققنا أكثر فسنجد أن حوالي 40 بالمئة
of the Earth's land surface is devoted to agriculture,
من مساحة سطح الأرض مخصصة للزراعة،
and it's 60 times larger
وهي أكبر 60 مرة
than all the areas we complain about,
من كل المناطق التي نشكو منها،
our suburban sprawl and our cities where we mostly live.
كضواحينا المتنامية ومدننا التي نعيش بها.
Half of humanity lives in cities today,
نصف البشر يقطنون اليوم بالمدن،
but a 60-times-larger area is used to grow food.
لكن المنطقة المستخدمة للزراعة الغذائية أكبر 60 مرة.
So this is an amazing kind of result,
وهذه نتيجة مدهشة،
and it really shocked us when we looked at that.
إذ كانت صدمة حقيقية لنا عندما توصلنا إليها.
So we're using an enormous amount of land for agriculture,
نحن نستخدم إذا مساحة كبيرة من الأرض للزراعة،
but also we're using a lot of water.
ولكننا نستخدم أيضا الكثير من المياه.
This is a photograph flying into Arizona,
هذه صورة جوية لأريزونا،
and when you look at it, you're like,
وعندما تنظرون إليها، تتساؤلون،
"What are they growing here?" It turns out
"ما الذي يزرعونه هناك؟" في الحقيقة
they're growing lettuce in the middle of the desert
يزرعون الخس بوسط الصحراء
using water sprayed on top.
باستخدام الري بالرش المدفعي.
Now, the irony is, it's probably sold
المضحك في الأمر الآن هو، أنها غالبا تباع
in our supermarket shelves in the Twin Cities.
على رفوف متاجرنا الكبرى بمدننا المتوأمة.
But what's really interesting is, this water's got to come
ولكن المثير للاهتمام حقا هو، تلك المياه قد جاءت
from some place, and it comes from here,
من مكان ما، لقد جاءت من هنا،
the Colorado River in North America.
نهر كولورادو بشمال أمريكا.
Well, the Colorado on a typical day in the 1950s,
هذا هو نهر كولورادو في يوم عادي سنة 1950،
this is just, you know, not a flood, not a drought,
هذا، كما تعلمون، ليس بفيضان أو جفاف،
kind of an average day, it looks something like this.
في يوم عادي هو يبدو بهذا الشكل.
But if we come back today, during a normal condition
ولكن إن عدنا للوقت الحاضر، في ظروف عادية
to the exact same location, this is what's left.
لنفس المكان بالضبط، هذا ما تبقى.
The difference is mainly irrigating the desert for food,
الفرق في الأساس بين استخدامه لري المحاصيل بالصحراء،
or maybe golf courses in Scottsdale, you take your pick.
أو ربما ملاعب الغولف بسكوتسديل، لكم أن تختاروا.
Well, this is a lot of water, and again, we're mining water
وهذا يعني الكثير من الماء، وبالتالي، استخراج المزيد منه
and using it to grow food,
واستخدمه في الزراعة الغذائية.
and today, if you travel down further down the Colorado,
واليوم، إن سافرتم جنوبا نحو مصب نهر كولورادو،
it dries up completely and no longer flows into the ocean.
سترون أنه جف تماما ولا يصب في البحر.
We've literally consumed an entire river in North America
لقد استنزفنا نهرا كاملا في شمال أمريكا
for irrigation.
من أجل الري.
Well, that's not even the worst example in the world.
لكنه ليس أسوء مثال في العالم.
This probably is: the Aral Sea.
بل على الأرجح هو: بحر الآرال.
Now, a lot you will remember this from your geography classes.
الكثير منكم درس عنه في الجغرافيا.
This is in the former Soviet Union
ويقع في الاتحاد السوفياتي سابقا
in between Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan,
بين كازاخستان وأوزبكستان،
one of the great inland seas of the world.
واحد من أكبر البحار الداخلية بالعالم.
But there's kind of a paradox here, because it looks like
ولكن هناك نوع من التناقض، فهو يبدو كأنه
it's surrounded by desert. Why is this sea here?
محاط بالصحراء. لما يتواجد هذا البحر هنا؟
The reason it's here is because, on the right-hand side,
سبب وجوده هناك هو أنه بالجانب الأيمن،
you see two little rivers kind of coming down
سترون نهرين صغيرين يجريان للأسفل
through the sand, feeding this basin with water.
بين الرمال، ويزودان هذا الحوض بالمياه.
Those rivers are draining snowmelt from mountains
هذين النهرين يجلبان الثلج الذائب بالجبال
far to the east, where snow melts, it travels down the river
البعيدة نحو الشرق، حيث يذوب الثلج، وينزل مع النهر
through the desert, and forms the great Aral Sea.
عبر الصحراء، لتشكل بحر الآرال الكبير.
Well, in the 1950s, the Soviets decided to divert that water
في العام 1950 قرر السوفيتيون تحويل مجرى النهر
to irrigate the desert to grow cotton, believe it or not,
صدقوا أو لا، لري القطن بالصحراء،
in Kazakhstan, to sell cotton to the international markets
بكازاخستان، لبيع القطن للأسواق العالمية
to bring foreign currency into the Soviet Union.
لتأمين العملة الأجنبية للاتحاد السوفياتي.
They really needed the money.
كانوا بحاجة ماسة للعملة.
Well, you can imagine what happens. You turn off
ويمكنكم تخيل ماذا حدث. توقفون
the water supply to the Aral Sea, what's going to happen?
تزويد بحر الآرال بالمياه، ما الذي سيحدث؟
Here it is in 1973,
هذا في العام 1973،
1986,
و1986
1999,
و1999
2004,
و2004
and about 11 months ago.
ومن حوالي 11 شهرا.
It's pretty extraordinary.
هذا مدهش بالفعل.
Now a lot of us in the audience here live in the Midwest.
الكثير من الحضور بيننا هنا يعيش بالغرب الأوسط،
Imagine that was Lake Superior.
تخيل أنها كانت بحيرة سوبيريور.
Imagine that was Lake Huron.
تخيل أنها كانت بحيرة هرون.
It's an extraordinary change.
هذا تغيير مذهل.
This is not only a change in water and
هذا ليس تغيير بالمياه و
where the shoreline is, this is a change in the fundamentals
مكان الشاطئ فحسب، بل هو تغييرفي العناصر الأساسية
of the environment of this region.
للبيئة بهذه الجهة.
Let's start with this.
دعونا نبدأ بهذا.
The Soviet Union didn't really have a Sierra Club.
الاتحاد السوفياتي لم يكن لديه نادي سييرا.
Let's put it that way.
فلنقلها بهذا الشكل.
So what you find in the bottom of the Aral Sea ain't pretty.
فما ستجدونه في قعر بحر الآرال ليس بالجميل.
There's a lot of toxic waste, a lot of things
هناك الكثير من النفايات السامة وغيرها من الأشياء
that were dumped there that are now becoming airborne.
الملقاة هناك والتي أصبحت الآن تحملها الرياح.
One of those small islands that was remote
واحدة من تلك الجزر الصغيرة التي كانت نائية
and impossible to get to was a site
وصعب الوصول إليها كانت موقعا
of Soviet biological weapons testing.
لاختبار أسلحة بيولوجية سوفيتية.
You can walk there today.
يمكنكم اليوم الذهاب إلى هناك مشيا.
Weather patterns have changed.
لقد تغيرت أنماط الطقس.
Nineteen of the unique 20 fish species found only
19 من أصل 20 نوع سمك كان موجودا
in the Aral Sea are now wiped off the face of the Earth.
ببحر الآرال فقط اختف من على وجه الأرض.
This is an environmental disaster writ large.
يتعلق الأمر بأكبر كارثة بيئية مسجلة.
But let's bring it home.
ولكن دعونا نعود للوطن.
This is a picture that Al Gore gave me a few years ago
هذه صورة أعطاها لي آل جور قبل بضع سنوات
that he took when he was in the Soviet Union
والتي التقطها عندما كان بالاتحاد السوفياتي
a long, long time ago,
منذ وقت طويل جدا،
showing the fishing fleets of the Aral Sea.
والتي تبين أساطيل الصيد ببحر الآرال.
You see the canal they dug?
هل تشاهدون القناة التي يحفرونها؟
They were so desperate to try to, kind of, float the boats into
كانوا يحاولون بيأس لجعل القوارب تطفوا
the remaining pools of water, but they finally had to give up
بالبرك المتبقية من المياه، ولكنهم في النهاية تخلو عنها
because the piers and the moorings simply couldn't
لأنه ببساطة الأرصفة والمراسي لم
keep up with the retreating shoreline.
تتمكن من ملائمة الشاطئ المتراجع.
I don't know about you, but I'm terrified that future
لا أعرف بالنسبة لكم، لكني مرعوب من أن علماء الأثار
archaeologists will dig this up and write stories about
بالمستقبل سيبحثون بهذا المكان وسيكتبون قصصا في
our time in history, and wonder, "What were you thinking?"
التاريخ عن عصرنا وسيتساءلون، "ما الذي كانوا يفكرون به؟"
Well, that's the future we have to look forward to.
فهذا هو المستقبل الذي يجب أن نتوقعه.
We already use about 50 percent of the Earth's fresh water
فقد استخدمنا بالفعل حوالي 50 بالمئة من المياه العذبة
that's sustainable, and agriculture alone
المستدامة بالأرض ، والزراعة وحدها
is 70 percent of that.
تستخدم 70 بالمئة منها.
So we use a lot of water, a lot of land for agriculture.
نحن نستخدم الكثير من المياه والأراضي للزراعة.
We also use a lot of the atmosphere for agriculture.
ونستخدم أيضا الكثير من الغلاف الجوي للزراعة
Usually when we think about the atmosphere,
عادة عندما نفكر بالغلاف الجوي،
we think about climate change and greenhouse gases,
فإننا نفكر في تغير المناخ والغازات الدفيئة
and mostly around energy,
وفي الغالب بما يتعلق بالطاقة،
but it turns out agriculture is one of the biggest emitters
ولكنه تبين أن الزراعة هي من أكبر مصادر
of greenhouse gases too.
الغازات الدفيئة أيضا.
If you look at carbon dioxide from
إذا نظرتم إلى ثاني أكسيد الكربون المنبعث
burning tropical rainforest,
من حرق الغابات المطيرة،
or methane coming from cows and rice,
أو الميثان الصادر عن الأبقار والأرز،
or nitrous oxide from too many fertilizers,
أو أكسيد النيتروز الصادر عن الإفراط بالأسمدة
it turns out agriculture is 30 percent of the greenhouse
فقد تبين أن الزراعة مصدر ل 30 بالمئة من الغازات الدفيئة
gases going into the atmosphere from human activity.
المنبعثة في الغلاف الجوي بسبب النشاط البشري.
That's more than all our transportation.
هذا أكثر من كل ما تصدره وسائل النقل.
It's more than all our electricity.
أكثر من كل ما يصدر عن الكهرباء.
It's more than all other manufacturing, in fact.
إنها أكثر مما تصدره كل الصناعات، وفي الواقع.
It's the single largest emitter of greenhouse gases
إنها أكبر مصدر للغازات الدفيئة
of any human activity in the world.
من أي نشاط بشري في العالم.
And yet, we don't talk about it very much.
ومع هذا لا نتحدث عنها بما يكفي حتى الآن.
So we have this incredible presence today of agriculture
لدينا اليوم هذا الانتشار المدهش والمهيمن
dominating our planet,
للزراعة على كوكبنا،
whether it's 40 percent of our land surface,
سواء كان ذلك ب 40 بالمئة من سطح الأرض
70 percent of the water we use,
أو 70 بالمئة من المياه التي نستخدمها
30 percent of our greenhouse gas emissions.
أو 30 بالمئة من انبعاث الغازات الدفيئة.
We've doubled the flows of nitrogen and phosphorus
فقد ضاعفنا انبعاث النيتروجين والفوسفور
around the world simply by using fertilizers,
حول العالم فقط باستخدامنا للأسمدة
causing huge problems of water quality from rivers,
مسببين مشاكل كبيرة بجودة مياه الأنهار
lakes, and even oceans, and it's also the single biggest
والبحيرات وحتى المحيطات، وهي أيضا أكبر
driver of biodiversity loss.
عامل مسبب لفقدان التنوع البيولوجي.
So without a doubt, agriculture is
وبدون شك، الزراعة هي
the single most powerful force unleashed on this planet
أكبر قوة أطلقت بهذا الكوكب
since the end of the ice age. No question.
منذ نهاية العصر الجليدي.
And it rivals climate change in importance.
بل تعادل قوة تغير المناخ من حيث الحجم.
And they're both happening at the same time.
وهما يحدثان بنفس الوقت.
But what's really important here to remember is that
ولكن الشيء المهم الذي يجب تذكره هو أن
it's not all bad. It's not that agriculture's a bad thing.
ليس كل شيء سلبي. الزراعة ليست أمرا سيئا.
In fact, we completely depend on it.
في الواقع، نحن نعتمد عليها كليا.
It's not optional. It's not a luxury. It's an absolute necessity.
وليست اختيارية. وليست ترفا بل ضرورة أساسية.
We have to provide food and feed and, yeah,
يجب علينا توفير الغذاء والعلف،
fiber and even biofuels to something like seven billion people
والألياف وحتى الوقود الحيوي لحوالي سبعة مليار شخص
in the world today, and if anything,
بالعالم اليوم، وإن لم يتغير شيء،
we're going to have the demands on agriculture
سيكون لدينا طلب مرتفع على الزراعة
increase into the future. It's not going to go away.
بالمستقبل. ولن يتراجع.
It's going to get a lot bigger, mainly because of
بل سيزداد أكثر بكثير، وخاصة بسبب
growing population. We're seven billion people today
ازدياد عدد السكان. نحن 7 بلايين اليوم
heading towards at least nine,
وحوالي 9 على الأقل،
probably nine and a half before we're done.
وربما 9 ونصف قبل أن نختفي.
More importantly, changing diets.
الأكثر أهمية هو تغيير العادات الغذائية.
As the world becomes wealthier as well as more populous,
فكلما ازداد ثراء العالم وعدد سكانه،
we're seeing increases in dietary consumption of meat,
سنشهد ارتفعا في استهلاك اللحم،
which take a lot more resources than a vegetarian diet does.
مما سيتطلب مصادر أكبر مما تقدمه الأنظمة الغذائية النباتية
So more people, eating more stuff, and richer stuff,
أي كلما استهلك واغتنى الناس أكثر
and of course having an energy crisis at the same time,
وبالطبع، المصحوبة بأزمة الطاقة،
where we have to replace oil with other energy sources
بحيث سيكون علينا تغيير النفط بمصادر طاقة أخرى
that will ultimately have to include some kinds of biofuels
التي ستشمل في النهاية بعض أنواع الوقود الحيوي
and bio-energy sources.
ومصادر الطاقة الحيوية.
So you put these together. It's really hard to see
اجمعوا بين كل هذا. سيكون من الصعب تصور
how we're going to get to the rest of the century
كيف يمكننا بلوغ نهاية ما تبقى من القرن
without at least doubling global agricultural production.
بدون مضاعفة الانتاج الزراعي العالمي على الأقل.
Well, how are we going to do this? How are going to
كيف سنحقق ذلك؟ كيف
double global ag production around the world?
سنضاعف من الإنتاج الزراعي حول العالم؟
Well, we could try to farm more land.
يمكننا محاولة زراعة المزيد من الأراضي.
This is an analysis we've done, where on the left is where
هذا تحليل أجريناه سابقا، هنا بالجهة اليسرى
the crops are today, on the right is where they could be
حيث المحاصيل اليوم، وباليمين حيث يجب أن تكون
based on soils and climate, assuming climate change
معتمدين على نوع التربة والمناخ، أخذين بعين الاعتبار
doesn't disrupt too much of this,
أن المناخ لم يتغير كثيرا عن اليوم،
which is not a good assumption.
وهي فرضية ليست دقيقة.
We could farm more land, but the problem is
يمكننا زرع المزيد من الأراضي، ولكن المشكلة هي
the remaining lands are in sensitive areas.
أن الأراضي المتبقية تتواجد بمناطق حساسة.
They have a lot of biodiversity, a lot of carbon,
بها تنوع بيولوجي كبير والكثير من الكربون
things we want to protect.
وهي أشياء نود حمايتها.
So we could grow more food by expanding farmland,
يمكننا إذا توسيع المساحات المزروعةلإنتاج المزيد من الغذاء،
but we'd better not,
ولكن من الأفضل عدم فعل ذلك،
because it's ecologically a very, very dangerous thing to do.
لأنه شيء خطير جدا إيكولوجيا.
Instead, we maybe want to freeze the footprint
بل، يمكننا إيقاف أثار
of agriculture and farm the lands we have better.
بزراعة أفضل الأراضي التي لدينا.
This is work that we're doing to try to highlight places
هذا هو العمل الذي سنقوم به كي نحاول إبراز الأماكن
in the world where we could improve yields
التي يمكن أن نرفع من مردودها
without harming the environment.
دون الإضرار بالبيئة.
The green areas here show where corn yields,
هذه المناطق هنا تبين حيث مردود الذرة،
just showing corn as an example,
نقدم الذرة على سبيل المثال فقط،
are already really high, probably the maximum you could
هو أصلا مرتفع، وعلى الأرجح أعلى ما يمكن
find on Earth today for that climate and soil,
بلوغه اليوم في المناخ والتربة الأرضيين،
but the brown areas and yellow areas are places where
ولكن المناطق البنية والصفراء هي أماكن
we're only getting maybe 20 or 30 percent of the yield
حيث لا نجني سوى 20 أو 30 بالمئة كمردود
you should be able to get.
يمكننا أن نحصل عليه.
You see a lot of this in Africa, even Latin America,
تلاحظون أن الكثير من المناطق هي بأفريقيا، وأمريكا الجنوبية،
but interestingly, Eastern Europe, where Soviet Union
ولكن المثير أن، أوروبا الشرقية، حيث كان
and Eastern Bloc countries used to be,
الاتحاد السوفياتي ودول الكتلة الشرقية،
is still a mess agriculturally.
زراعيا مازالت في فوضى.
Now, this would require nutrients and water.
وهذا يتطلب المغذيات والماء.
It's going to either be organic or conventional
وهي ستكون طبيعية وتقليدية
or some mix of the two to deliver that.
أو تجمع بين الإثنين.
Plants need water and nutrients.
النباتات بحاجة للماء والمغذيات.
But we can do this, and there are opportunities to make this work.
لكن يمكننا فعل ذلك، فهناك فرص لجعل ذلك يعمل.
But we have to do it in a way that is sensitive
ولكن يجب أن نقوم بذلك بشكل عقلاني
to meeting the food security needs of the future
لتلبية حاجيات الأمن الغذائي
and the environmental security needs of the future.
والأمن البيئي في المستقبل.
We have to figure out how to make this tradeoff between
حيث يجب علينا البحث عن حل وسط بين
growing food and having a healthy environment work better.
الزراعة الغذائية والبيئة السليمة.
Right now, it's kind of an all-or-nothing proposition.
في الوقت الراهن، هي مسألة كل شيء أو لا شيء.
We can grow food in the background --
يمكننا زرع الأغذية في الخلف --
that's a soybean field —
هذا حقل فول صويا --
and in this flower diagram, it shows we grow a lot of food,
يبين هذا الرسم البياني أننا نزرع الكثير من المحاصيل،
but we don't have a lot clean water, we're not storing
ولكن ليس لدينا الكثير من المياه النقية، ولا نخزن
a lot of carbon, we don't have a lot of biodiversity.
الكثير من الكربون، وليس لدينا الكثير من التنوع البيولوجي.
In the foreground, we have this prairie
في الواجهة، لدينا هذا المرعى
that's wonderful from the environmental side,
الجميل من الناحية البيئية،
but you can't eat anything. What's there to eat?
ولكن يمكنكم أكل أي شيء. ماذا يوجد هناك لأكله؟
We need to figure out how to bring both of those together
نحتاج إلى حل للجمع بين الجانبين
into a new kind of agriculture that brings them all together.
في نوع جديد من الزراعة.
Now, when I talk about this, people often tell me,
عندما أتحدث حول هذا الموضوع، فإن الناس غالبا ما يقولون لي،
"Well, isn't blank the answer?" -- organic food,
"الأجوبة عديدة؟" -- كالطعام العضوي،
local food, GMOs, new trade subsidies, new farm bills --
الطعام المحلي، والكائنات المعدلة جينيا، والمنتجات البديلة، وتقنين الزراعة --
and yeah, we have a lot of good ideas here,
نعم، لدينا هنا الكثير من الأفكار الجيدة،
but not any one of these is a silver bullet.
ولكن ولا واحدة منها هي العلاج السحري.
In fact, what I think they are is more like silver buckshot.
في الواقع، أعتقد أنها سلة متنوعة المحتوى.
And I love silver buckshot. You put it together
وأنا أحب مبدأ التنويع. فأنت تضعها مع بعضها
and you've got something really powerful,
وستحصل على شيء قوي جدا،
but we need to put them together.
ولكن نحن بحاجة لوضعها معا.
So what we have to do, I think, is invent a new kind
لدى ما علينا فعله، كما أعتقد، هو خلق نوع جديد
of agriculture that blends the best ideas
من الزراعة يجمع بين أفضل أفكار
of commercial agriculture and the green revolution
الزراعة التجارية والثورة الخضراء
with the best ideas of organic farming and local food
ومع أفضل أفكار الزراعة العضوية والمحلية
and the best ideas of environmental conservation,
وأفضل أفكار الحماية البيئية،
not to have them fighting each other but to have them
ليس لجعلها تتنافس معا بل لجعلها
collaborating together to form a new kind of agriculture,
تتعاون معا لخلق نوع جديد من الزراعة،
something I call "terraculture," or farming for a whole planet.
شيء أسميه "طراكلتر" أو الزراعة لكوكب كامل.
Now, having this conversation has been really hard,
كانت هذه المحادثة صعبة جدا،
and we've been trying very hard to bring these key points
ونحن نحاول بشدة لتقديم هذه النقاط الرئيسية
to people to reduce the controversy,
للناس حتى نحد من الخلاف
to increase the collaboration.
ونزيد من التعاون.
I want to show you a short video that does kind of show
أود أن أريكم فيديو قصير يبين
our efforts right now to bring these sides together
الجهود التي نقوم بها للتقريب بين الجانبين
into a single conversation. So let me show you that.
للحوار حول طاولة واحدة. دعوني أريكم ذلك.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
("Institute on the Environment, University of Minnesota: Driven to Discover")
("معهد البيئة، جامعة مينيسوتا: الدفع نحو الاكتشاف")
("The world population is growing
("سكان العالم يزدادون
by 75 million people each year.
بمعدل 75 مليون شخص سنويا.
That's almost the size of Germany.
هذا يقارب حجم ألمانيا.
Today, we're nearing 7 billion people.
اليوم، نحن نقترب من 7 مليارات نسمة.
At this rate, we'll reach 9 billion people by 2040.
بهذه الوتيرة، سنبلغ 9 مليارت نسمة مع العام 2040.
And we all need food.
سنحتاج جميعا للغذاء.
But how?
لكن كيف؟
How do we feed a growing world without destroying the planet?
كيف يمكننا إطعام العالم بدون تدمير الكوكب؟
We already know climate change is a big problem.
نحن نعلم أن تغير المناخ هو مشكل كبير.
But it's not the only problem.
لكنه ليس الوحيد.
We need to face 'the other inconvenient truth.'
يجب أن نواجه "الحقيقة الأخرى المزعجة."
A global crisis in agriculture.
أزمة زراعة عالمية.
Population growth + meat consumption + dairy consumption + energy costs + bioenergy production = stress on natural resources.
تزايد السكان + استهلاك اللحوم + استهلاك منتجات الحليب + تكاليف الطاقة + إنتاج الطاقة الحيوية = الضغط على الموارد الطبيعية.
More than 40% of Earth's land has been cleared for agriculture.
أكثر من 40 بالمئة من أراضي الكوكب موجهة للزراعة.
Global croplands cover 16 million km².
تغطي الأراضي المزروعة إجمالي 16 مليون كلم مربع.
That's almost the size of South America.
حوالي مساحة أمريكا الجنوبية.
Global pastures cover 30 million km².
تغطي المراعي إجمالي 30 مليون كلم مربع.
That's the size of Africa.
وهو بحجم أفريقيا.
Agriculture uses 60 times more land than urban and suburban areas combined.
مساحة الزراعة 60 مرة أكبر من المناطق الحضرية والشبه حضرية معا.
Irrigation is the biggest use of water on the planet.
الري هو أكبر مستهلك للماء في الكوكب.
We use 2,800 cubic kilometers of water on crops every year.
نستخدم 2800 كلم مكعب من المياه للمحاصيل سنويا.
That's enough to fill 7,305 Empire State Buildings every day.
ما يكفي لملء 7305 مرة مبنى إمباير ستيت يوميا.
Today, many large rivers have reduced flows.
اليوم، العديد من الأنهر قد نقص صبيبها.
Some dry up altogether.
وبعضها جف بالفعل.
Look at the Aral Sea, now turned to desert.
أنظروا لبحر الآرال يتحول لصحراء.
Or the Colorado River, which no longer flows to the ocean.
أو نهر كولورادوا، الذي لم يعد يصب بالمحيط.
Fertilizers have more than doubled the phosphorus and nitrogen in the environment.
الأسمدة زادت من الفوسفور والنيتروجين بالبيئة لأكثر من الضعف.
The consequence?
وما هي النتيجة؟
Widespread water pollution
انتشار كبير لتلوث الماء
and massive degradation of lakes and rivers.
وتدهور هائل للبحيرات والأنهر.
Surprisingly, agriculture is the biggest contributor to climate change.
والمدهش، الزراعة هي أكبر مساهم في التغير المناخي.
It generates 30% of greenhouse gas emissions.
تصدر 30 بالمئة من الغازات الدفيئة.
That's more than the emissions from all electricity and industry,
وهذا أكثر مما يصدر عن الكهرباء والصناعة.
or from all the world's planes, trains and automobiles.
أو عن طائرات العالم كلها، والقطارات والسيارات.
Most agricultural emissions come from tropical deforestation,
وأهم مصادرها ناتجة عن إزالة الغابة الاستوائية،
methane from animals and rice fields,
والميثان عن الحيوانات وحقول الأرز،
and nitrous oxide from over-fertilizing.
وأكسيد النيتروز عن الإفراط بالأسمدة.
There is nothing we do that transforms the world more than agriculture.
ليس هناك شيء نقوم به يغير العالم أكثر من الزراعة.
And there's nothing we do that is more crucial to our survival.
وليس هناك شيء نقوم به أكثر أهمية من بقائنا أحياء.
Here's the dilemma...
هذه هي المعضلة...
As the world grows by several billion more people,
بينما يزداد العالم ببضعة مليارات من الناس،
We'll need to double, maybe even triple, global food production.
سيجب علينا مضاعفة، وربما لثلاثة أضعاف، الإنتاج الغذائي العالمي.
So where do we go from here?
إذا أين سنذهب بكل هذا؟
We need a bigger conversation, an international dialogue.
نحتاج إلى حوار كبير، حوار دولي.
We need to invest in real solutions:
يجب أن نستثمر في الحلول الحقيقية:
incentives for farmers, precision agriculture, new crop varieties, drip irrigation,
تحفيز المزارعين، والزراعة الدقيقة، وأنواع جديدة من المحاصيل، والري بالتنقيط،
gray water recycling, better tillage practices, smarter diets.
إعادة تدوير المياه الرمادية، والحرث الجيد، وأنظمة غذائية ذكية.
We need everyone at the table.
نحتاج جلوس الجميع حول الطاولة.
Advocates of commercial agriculture,
ممثلي الزراعة التجارية،
environmental conservation,
والمحافظة على البيئة،
and organic farming...
والزراعة العضوية...
must work together.
يجب عليهم العمل معا.
There is no single solution.
ليس هناك حل فردي.
We need collaboration,
نحتاج للتعاون،
imagination,
والابتكار،
determination,
والعزيمة،
because failure is not an option.
لأن الفشل ليس خيارا.
How do we feed the world without destroying it?
كيف سنطعم العالم بدون تدميره؟
Yeah, so we face one of the greatest grand challenges
نحن اليوم أمام واحد من أكبر التحديات لدينا
in all of human history today:
في كل تاريخ البشرية:
the need to feed nine billion people
الحاجة لإطعام 9 مليار شخص
and do so sustainably and equitably and justly,
وذلك بشكل دائم ومنصف وعادل،
at the same time protecting our planet
وبنفس الوقت حماية كوكبنا
for this and future generations.
لهذا الجيل والأجيال القادمة.
This is going to be one of the hardest things
وهو واحد من أصعب الأشياء التي
we ever have done in human history,
سنقوم بها في تاريخ البشرية،
and we absolutely have to get it right,
ويجب علينا القيام بها على أكمل وجه،
and we have to get it right on our first and only try.
ويجب القيام بذلك في المحاولة الوحيدة بين أيدينا، ومن المرة الأولى.
So thanks very much. (Applause)
أشكركم جزيلا. (تصفيق)